# Henrik Wilhelmsen

Strömstad, Vastra Gotaland County, Sweden



contact@henrikwilhelmsen.com



linkedin.com/in/wilhelmsenhenrik



http://henrikwilhelmsen.com/

### Summary

Technical animator with over 6 years of experience working with animation in games.

Competent Python programmer and highly proficient in most relevant DCC software and several game engines.

Worked on every in-game cut-scene in Rage 2 while at Avalanche, and was part of the animation and motion capture process all the way from story to implementation.

At Ubisoft Stockholm I have helped develop the dialogue system for Avatar: Frontiers of Pandora, and have most recently been managing and developing the animation pipeline for an unannounced title.

### **Experience**



#### **Technical Animator**

Ubisoft Stockholm Sep 2021 - Present (1 year 7 months)



Ubisoft Stockholm Jan 2019 - Sep 2021 (2 years 9 months)

## Experienced Animator

Avalanche Studios Group Apr 2018 - Dec 2018 (9 months)

## Junior Animator

Avalanche Studios Group Apr 2017 - Apr 2018 (1 year 1 month)

#### **Education**



### Inland Norway University of Applied Sciences

Bachelor's degree, Animation 2012 - 2015



Games Workshop 1, Game Animation 2016 - 2016



Games Workshop 2, Game Animation 2016 - 2016

### **Skills**

Python (Programming Language) • PySide • Autodesk Maya • Autodesk MotionBuilder • Unreal Engine • Motion capture • Character Rigging • Animation • Character Animation • Game Development